Abraham: So, let’s look at some of the
key sectors that offer good motivation
for attack from cyber criminals.
Nicole: Cyber attacks against businesses
and organisations are often deliberate
and motivated by financial gain but they
may also include other motivations like
making a political or ideological point.
They may also be involved in espionage
either industrial or state sponsored.
They may even do it because they
can and show the world their skills.
Abraham: They mainly involve outside
entities or but can also involve
insider threats attacks from disgruntled
employees or covert threat actors.
Nicole: All sectors are vulnerable to
cyber-attack but he key sectors most
vulnerable are businesses, healthcare,
government, Energy and education.
We all hear about the high-profile attacks
on media companies like Netflix and
Sony and many on financial institutions.
For companies like this cyber security is
looked on as key to their systems however
smaller businesses and organisations
are probably more susceptible.
Abraham: Healthcare organisations offer
hackers millions of patient records to
be sold on the dark net and because their
security is not equipped to withstand
these threats, they are an easy target.
Many have old systems that have unpatched
vulnerabilities and transfer patient
records that could themselves hold malware
infecting the whole healthcare system.
Nicole: Government agencies hold
loads of confidential information
which is also shared between agencies
which have vulnerabilities in their
servers and databases opening the
doors to many attacks to gain access.
And offering a lucrative haul.
The energy industries have large
networks open to cyber attack which
can undermine security and affect
millions of consumers or industries.
Abraham: Educational establishments
have a mine of information stored
which can easily be accessed by hackers
Any companies that store sensitive data
of any kind are at risk but especially
those who transfer that data and whose
systems are potentially out of date
or suffer from many vulnerabilities.
Nicole: Hackers are motivated on
the whole by financial gain, and
this may be by selling personal
records or state secrets or holding
organisations and companies to ransom.
The easier it is to gain access the more
motivation they have to try and therefore
these organisations are more at risk.